Guide to the George McTurnan Kahin collection on the origins of the Vietnam war, ca. 1954-1970.
Kahin, George McTurnan collection on the origins of the Vietnam War,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George McT. Kahin collection on the origins of the Vietnam war, [ca. 1954-1970], 1961-1970 (bulk)
4251
George McTurnan Kahin.
133 v., 5.6 cubic ft.
Copies of government documents.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Copies of United States government documents pertaining to the war in Vietnam, collected by Professor Kahin through the Freedom of Information Act for use in his 1986 book Intervention: How America Became Involved in Vietnam. For the pre-1961 period, the largest single group of documents relates to the Geneva Conference in 1954. Although the majority of documents relate to Vietnam, there is also coverage of Cambodia and Laos, particularly during the period from 1961 to 1963.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Copies of United States government documents pertaining to the war in Vietnam, collected by Professor Kahin through the Freedom of Information Act for use in his 1986 book Intervention: How America Became Involved in Vietnam. For the pre-1961 period, the largest single group of documents relates to the Geneva Conference in 1954. Although the majority of documents relate to Vietnam, there is also coverage of Cambodia and Laos, particularly during the period from 1961 to 1963.
Categories of documents include cable traffic between the U.S. Embassies in Saigon, Phnom Penh, and Vientiane and the Department of State; cables from the U.S. military command in Saigon; CIA cables and Situation Reports, both day-to-day coverage of specific events and crises, and weekly reports of political and military developments; internal documents from the White House, including National Security memos and other memos between Administration officials, as well as transcripts of meetings between Presidents Kennedy and Johnson and their advisors; and documents from meetings and conferences between U.S. leaders and the leaders of South Vietnam.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kahin, George McTurnan.
Subjects:
Vietnam War, 1961-1975.
Places:
Vietnam--Politics and government--1945-1975.; United States--Foreign relations--Vietnam.; Vietnam--Foreign relations--United States.; Laos--Foreign relations--United States.; Cambodia--Foreign relations--United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
See also George McTurnan Kahin. Papers, #14-27-3146
CONTAINER LIST
- Strategic/Geopolitical Considerations (Volume 1)
- Counterinsurgency, 1961 (Volume 2)
- Escalation: Jan.-June 1961 (Volume 3)
- Escalation: July-Oct. 1961 (Volume 4)
- Escalation: Nov, 1961-1962 (Volume 5)
- Escalation Plans, 1961 (Volume 6)
- U.S. Aid - Military (Volume 7)
- U.S. Efforts to Promote Reform: Policies - J.F.K. (Volume 8)
- Third Country: General, 1961 (Volume 9)
- Public Opinion: General (Volume 10)
- U.S. Perception Diem Government (Volume 11)
- U.S. Perception Diem Government (Volume 12)
- Evaluation: D.R.V., 1961 (Volume 13)
- Negotiated Settlement: U.S. Positions, 1961 (Volume 14)
- Southeast Asia: Overall (Volume 15)
- L.B.J. Visit to Asia (Volume 16)
- Reports of U.S. Officials. 3. Taylor Mission - Oct. & Nov. 1961: Reports (Volume 17)
- Reports of U.S. Officials. 3. Taylor Mission - A. Jordan Report: White Paper, Oct. 1961 (Volume 18)
- Cambodia - U.S. Relations, pre-1963 (Volume 19)
- Laos - Undermining of Agreement, 1962 (Volume 22)
- Laos - Thailand (Volume 23)
- Thailand - General, 1961 (Volume 24)
- Thai - U.S. Relations - Military Support (Volume 25)
- Thailand: Thailand - Laos (Volume 26)
- Cambodia: Chronology, 1960-1963 (Volume 27)
- Laos: Chronology, 1962-1963 (Volume 29)
- Southeast Asia - Chronology, 1960-1962 (Volume 30)
- Thailand: Chronolgy, 1961 (Volume 31)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Jan.-Apr. 1961 (Volume 32)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, June-July 1961 (Volume 33)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Aug.-Sept. 1961 (Volume 34)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Oct. 1961 (Volume 35)
- Taylor Mission Report, Oct.-Nov. 1961 (Volume 36)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Nov. 1-15, 1961 (Volume 37)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Nov. 16-30, 1961 (Volume 38)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Dec. 1961 (Volume 39)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Jan.-Dec. 1962 (Volume 40)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Jan. 1964 (Volume 41)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Feb. 1964 (Volume 42)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Mar. 1-16, 1964 (Volume 43)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Mar. 17-31, 1964 (Volume 44)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Apr. 1964 (Volume 45)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, May 1-17, 1964 (Volume 46)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, May 18-31, 1964 (Volume 47)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, June 1964 (Volume 48)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, July 1-22, 1964 (Volume 49)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, July 23-31, 1964 (Volume 50)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Aug. 1-10, 1964 (Volume 51)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Aug. 11-31, 1964 (Volume 52)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Sept. 1-14, 1964 (Volume 53)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Sept. 15-30, 1964 (Volume 54)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Oct. 1964 (Volume 55)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Nov. 1964 (Volume 56)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Dec. 1-22, 1964 (Volume 57)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Dec. 23-31, 1964 (Volume 58)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Jan. 1-21, 1965 (Volume 59)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Jan. 22-31, 1965 (Volume 60)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Feb. 1-3, 1965 (Volume 61)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Feb. 4-10, 1965 (Volume 62)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Feb. 11-18, 1965 (Volume 63)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy. Feb. 19-28, 1965 (Volume 64)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Mar. 1-19, 1965 (Volume 65)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Mar. 20-31, 1965 (Volume 66)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Apr. 1-14, 1965 (Volume 67)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Apr. 15-30, 1965 (Volume 68)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, May 1965 (Volume 69)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, June 1-11, 1965 (Volume 70)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, June 12-30, 1965 (Volume 71)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, July 1965 (Volume 72)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Aug.-Dec. 1965 (Volume 73)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Jan.-Feb. 1966 (Volume 74)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Mar. 1966 (Volume 75)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Apr. 1966 (Volume 76)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, May-June 1966 (Volume 77)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, July-Dec. 1966 (Volume 78)
- Vietnam: Chronolgy, Feb. 1967-Oct. 1968 (Volume 79)
- CIA - Situation Reports South Vietnam, Dec. 1963-May 1964 (Volume 80)
- CIA - Situation Reports South Vietnam, June-Aug. 1964 (Volume 81)
- CIA - Situation Reports South Vietnam, Sept.-Nov. 1964 (Volume 82)
- CIA - Situation Reports South Vietnam, Dec. 1964-Feb. 1965 (Volume 83)
- CIA - Situation Reports South Vietnam, Mar. 1965-June 1966 (Volume 84)
- Escalation: I. Commitment of U.S. Ground Forces II. Change to Offensive Operations (Volume 85)
- Johnson Administration: Management of Public Opinion (Volume 86)
- U.S. Perception of Nguyen Khanh (Volume 87)
- Laos: I. General II. Undermining of the 1962 Geneva Agreements III. Laos and the Vietnam War (Volume 88)
- Covert Operations Against North Vietnam (Volume 89)
- Thailand (Volume 90)
- U.S. Evaluation of the DRV (Volume 91)
- Political Role of the Armed Forces (Volume 92)
- Montagnard Revolt of 19-25 Sept. 1964 (Volume 93)
- Promotion of Civilian Governments by the U.S. (Volume 94)
- Negotiations: DRV/NLF Attitudes and Positions (Volume 95)
- Negotiations: US/GVN Attitudes and Positions (Volume 96)
- U.S. Embassy, Saigon: Weekly Reports, Mar. 1964-Jan. 1965 (Volume 97)
- The Soviet Factor (Volume 98)
- The China Factor (Volume 99)
- Third Country Support of U.S. (Volume 100)
- Neutralism as a Political Force (Volume 101)
- Ky/Thieu Coup, June 1965 (Volume 102)
- Pham Ngoc Thao's Abortive Coup, May 1965 (Volume 103)
- U.S. Perception of Nguyen Cao Ky and Nguyen Van Thieu (Volume 104)
- LBJ: Public Statements of the War (Volume 105)
- JFK Weekend Papers, Apr. 1961-July 1962 (Volume 106)
- Special Position of Henry Cabot Lodge in the Johnson Administration (Volume 107)
- Information Policy (Volume 108)
- Strategic Considerations (Volume 109)
- U.S. Aid to South Vietnam (Volume 110)
- Dean Rusk's Appointment Calendar (Volume 111)
- Catholics as a Political Force (Volume 112)
- Cambodia: The Question of Border Violations (Volume 113)
- Southeast Asia: Overall Assessments (Volume 114)
- Interpretations and Violations of the 1954 Geneva Accords (Volume 115)
- Biographies of Prominent Vietnamese (Volume 116)
- World Opinion (Volume 117)
- Biographies: Civilian (Volume 118)
- Cambodia: I. General; II. Termination of U.S. Aid; III. Termination of Diplomatic Relations with U.S.; IV. Relations with NLF/DRV (Volume 119)
- Bombing: I. Plans; II. Implementation; III. Evaluation (Volume 120)
- Air Strikes, Unconventional Weapons (Volume 121)
- Reports of Special Missions of U.S. Officials (Volume 122)
- U.S. Evaluation of the NLF (Volume 123)
- Escaltion (Plans/Scenarios) (Volume 124)
- Coup Attempt of Feb. 1965 and the Removal of Nguyen Khanh (Volume 125)
- Gen. Nguyen Khanh's Coup, 31 Jan. 1964 (Volume 126)
- U.S. Perception of Duong Van Minh (Volume 127)
- Counterinsurgency - Strategic Hamlets - Pacification (Volume 128)
- Generals' Abortive Coup Attempt, 13-14 Sept. 1965 (Volume 129)
- Gulf of Tonkin Incident (Volume 130)
- Political Role of the Buddhists (Volume 131)
- Buddhist "Struggle Movement", Mar.-Apr. 1966 (Volume 132)
- Biographies (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Vol. 1 pre-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Vol. 2 U.S. speech, Feb. 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Vol. 3 Feb.-May 23, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Vol. 4 May 25-Nov. 1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Vol. 5 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Vol. 6 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Vol. 7A 1960-Apr. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Vol. 8 May 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Vol. 9 Jan.-Sept. 15, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Vol. 10 Sept. 16-Dec. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Vol. 11Jan.-Aug. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Vol. 12Aug.-Nov. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Vol. 13 Nov. 1964 - Bundy drafts (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Vol. 14 Dec. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Vol. 15 Jan.-Feb. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Vol. 16 Mar. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Vol. 17 Apr.-May 15, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Vol. 18 May 16-31, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Vol. 19 June-July 15, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Vol. 20 July 16-Dec. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Vol. 21 Jan.-Feb. 1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Vol. 22 Mar.-Apr. 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Vol. 23 May-Sept. 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Vol. 24 Oct.-Dec. 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Vol. 25 Jan.-May 1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Vol. 26 June-Aug. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Vol. 27 Sept.-Dec. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Vol. 28 Jan.-Mar. 3, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Vol. 29 Mar. 4-Dec. 1968; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- I.A. Strategy/Geopolitical considerations B. China factor, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 1)
- I.C. Strategy: Soviet factor, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 2)
- II.A. Counterinsurgency, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 3)
- II.A. Counterinsurgency II.B. Covert operations against the North, 1962 (Box 3, Volume 4)
- II.D. Escalation, 1961-01-1961-06 (Box 3, Volume 5)
- II.D. Escalation, 1961-07-1961-10 (Box 3, Volume 6)
- II.D. Escalation, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Volume 7)
- II.D.1.A. Escalation: Plans, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 8)
- II.D.1.B. Escalation: Actions 1.C. Escalation: US combat troops II.F. Escalation: unconventional weapons: defoliants, Napalm, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 9)
- III.A. US aid: military, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 10)
- III.A. US aid: economic, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 11)
- IV.A. Policies under JFK: political, military, economic, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 12)
- V.A. Third country: general D. Third country: SEATO, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 13)
- VI.A. Public opinion: general B.1. Public opinion: JFK C. World opinion, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 14)
- VII.A. US perception of the Diem government, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 15)
- VII.A. US perception of the Diem government, 1961 (Box 3, Volume 15)
- VII.A. US perception of the Diem government VII.B. US perception of the Minh government, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 15A)
- VII.B. US perception of the Diem government VII.G. Anti-Diem sentiment: general VII.E. Coup against Diem, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 16)
- VII.G. Anti-Diem sentiment VII.E. Coup against Diem, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 16A)
- VII.B. US perception of the Diem government VII.G. Anti-Diem sentiment VII.E. Coup against Diem, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 16B)
- VII.E. Coup against Diem (1.), 1961 (Box 4, Volume 17)
- VII.E. Coup against Diem, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 18)
- VII.L. Evaluation of the DRY-1961 VII.M. Evaluation of NLF (VC)-Military VII.N. Evaluation: RVM military, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 19)
- VIII.A. Negotiated settlement - US positions VIII.C.1. 1954 Geneva accords - I.C.C. VIII.C.2. 1954 Geneva accords interpretations / violations, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 20)
- IX.A. Southeast Asia: overall assessments, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 21)
- IX.D.1. LBJ visit to Asia D.2. Staley Mission / reports mid-1961 IX.D.3. Craig Report, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Volume 22)
- IX.D. Reports of US officials 3. Taylor mission, reports, 1961-10-1961-11 (Box 4, Volume 23)
- IX.D. Reports of US officials 3. Taylor mission. A. Jordan report - White paper IX.E. Government appraisals, 1961-10-1962 (Box 4, Volume 24)
- X.A. General: public statements on the war. JFK X.F. General miscellaneous, bilateral treaty, infiltration XI.A.1.a Cambodia-U.S. Relations pre-1963, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 25)
- XI.B.1. Laos-Perception of importance / Near intervention, 1961 (Box 4, Volume 27)
- XI.B.2. Laos-background and negotiation of 1962 Geneva Agreement, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Volume 28)
- XI.B.2. Laos-background and negotiation of 1962 Geneva Agreement, 1962 (Box 5, Volume 29)
- XI.B.4. Laos-Vietnam, 1962 (Box 5, Volume 30)
- XI.B.5. Laos-Thailand B.6. Laos-SEATO, 1962 (Box 5, Volume 31)
- XI.C.1. Thailand: general 1.b. Thailand-KMT 1.c.c. Thailand-regional cooperation XI.C.1.d. Thailand-miscellaneous XI.C.2.a. Thai-US relations-SEATO XI.C.2.b. US-Thai Relations Rusk-Thanat agreement, 1962 (Box 5, Volume 32)
- XI.C.2.c. Thai-US relations - military support 2.d. counterinsurgency, 1962 (Box 5, Volume 33)
- XI.C.2.e. Thai-US relation - economic assistance C.3. Thailand-Laos C.4. Thailand-Cambodia C.5. Thailand-Vietnam C.6. Thailand-biographies, 1962 (Box 5, Volume 34)
- Laos chronology, 1961-01-1961-06 (Box 5, Volume 36)
- Laos chronology, 1962 (Box 5, Volume 37)
- Laos chronology, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Volume 38)
- South East Asia chronology, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Volume 39)
- Thailand chronology, 1961-1962-03-07 (Box 5, Volume 41)
- Thailand chronology, 1962-03-08-1962-04 (Box 5, Volume 42)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-01-1961-04 (Box 5, Volume 43)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-05 (Box 5, Volume 44)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-06-1961-07 (Box 5, Volume 45)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-07-1961-09 (Box 6, Volume 46)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-10 (Box 6, Volume 47)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-10-1961-11 (Box 6, Volume 48)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-11-01-1961-11-15 (Box 6, Volume 49)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-11-16-1961-11-30 (Box 7, Volume 50)
- Vietnam chronology, 1961-12 (Box 7, Volume 51)
- Vietnam chronology, 1963-11 (Box 7, Volume 54)
- Vietnam chronology JFK public statements on the war, 1963 (Box 7, Volume 55)
- Indonesia's government estates and their master's, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)